Joshua Logan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Joshua Logan Papers 1723-1992 (bulk 1940-1980)
MSS80138
Logan, Joshua
44,650 items
184 containers plus 37 oversize
88 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Theatrical producer and director and playwright. Correspondence, family papers, business and financial papers, production files, writings, publicity material, clippings, scrapbooks, and other papers documenting Logan's career as producer, director, and author of theatrical, musical, and motion picture productions, chiefly from 1940 to 1980.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Arthur, Zinn--Correspondence.; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989--Correspondence.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971--Correspondence.; Hammerstein, Oscar, II, 1895-1960--Correspondence.; Hayward, Leland, 1902-1971--Correspondence.; Inge, William--Correspondence.; Logan, Joshua.; Logan, Nedda Harrigan--Correspondence.; Martin, Mary, 1913-1990--Correspondence.; Michener, James A. (James Albert), 1907-1997--Correspondence.; Mielziner, Jo, 1901-1976--Correspondence.; Noble, Sue Nabors--Correspondence.; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979--Correspondence.; Russell, Rosalind--Correspondence.; Smith, Lois Noble--Correspondence.; Stewart, James, 1908-1997--Correspondence.; Williams, Emlyn, 1905-1987--Correspondence.
Subjects
Motion pictures--Production and direction.; Musical films--Production and direction.; Musicals--Production and direction.; Theater--Production and direction.
Occupations
Dramatists.; Theatrical directors.; Theatrical producers.
Provenance
The papers of Joshua Logan, author and theater and motion picture director and producer, were received as a bequest from Logan to the Library of Congress in 1989 and 1990.
Additional Guides
A description of the Logan Papers appears in Library of Congress Acquisitions: Manuscript Division, 1990, pp. 39-44.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Audio disks and cassettes, reel-to-reel audiotapes, Dictaphone machines and belts, films, and videotapes have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. Librettos, sheet music, and printed and manuscript scores have been transferred to the Music Division. Posters, postcards, and some photographs and drawings have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Joshua Logan Papers.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1908, Oct. 5 Born, Texarkana, Tex.
1927 Diploma, Culver Military Academy, Culver, Ind.
1927 1931 Attended Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
1928 1935 Actor, codirector, University Players, Falmouth, Mass.
1931 Studied under Konstantin Stanislavsky,; Moscow Art Theatre, Moscow, USSR
1938 Director, On Borrowed Time, a play by Paul Osborn Director, I Married an Angel, a play by Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart Director, Knickerbocker Holiday, a play by Maxwell Anderson
1940 Married Barbara O'Neil (divorced 1941) Director, Charley's Aunt, a play by Brandon Thomas
1942 1945 Captain, United States Army Air Corps
1945 Married Grace (Nedda) Harrigan Connolly
1946 Director, Annie Get Your Gun, a play by Herbert and Dorothy Fields Director, Happy Birthday, a play by Anita Loos
1947 Director, John Loves Mary, a play by Norman Krasna
1948 Director, coauthor, Mister Roberts, a play by Thomas Heggen and Joshua Logan
1949 Director, coauthor, coproducer, South Pacific, a play by Oscar Hammerstein and Joshua Logan
1950 Pulitzer Prize, coauthor, South Pacific Tony Award, Best Director, South Pacific Director, author, coproducer, The Wisteria Trees
1952 Director, coauthor, coproducer, Wish You Were Here, a play by Arthur Kober and Joshua Logan
1953 Director, coproducer, Picnic, a play by William Inge Director, producer, Kind Sir, a play by Norman Krasna
1954 Director, coauthor, coproducer, Fanny, a play by S. N. Behrman and Joshua Logan
1955 Director, Picnic, a Columbia Pictures film Golden Globe Award, Best Director, Picnic
1956 Director, Bus Stop, a Twentieth Century-Fox film
1957 Director, Sayonara, a Warner Brothers film Director, South Pacific, a Magna-Twentieth Century-Fox film
1958 Director, coproducer, The World of Suzy Wong, a play by Paul Osborn
1961 Director, producer, Fanny, a Warner Brothers film
1962 Director, Mr. President, a play by Howard Lindsay and Russel Crouse
1964 Director, producer, Ensign Pulver, a Warner Brothers film
1967 Director, Camelot, a Warner Brothers film
1969 Director, Paint Your Wagon, a Paramount Pictures film
1974 Director, coauthor, coproducer, Miss Moffat, a play by Emlyn Williams and Joshua Logan
1976 Author, Josh; My Up and Down, In and Out Life (New York: Delacorte Press. 408 pp.) Director, author, lyricist, Rip Van Winkle, a play
1978 Author, Movie Stars, Real People, and Me (New York: Delacorte Press. 368 pp.)
1982 Director, translator, Carmen, an opera by Georges Bizet, performed by Shreveport Symphony Orchestra, Shreveport, La.
1983 Director, author, Huck and Jim on the Mississippi, a play
1983 1986 Instructor, Department of Theatre, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, Fla.
1988, July 12 Died, New York, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Joshua Lockwood Logan (1908-1988) span the years 1723-1992, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1940-1980. The collection documents Logan's career as a director, producer, and author of stage and film productions. Included are family papers, correspondence, business papers, financial papers, production records, writings, and scrapbooks.
The Family Papers series contains correspondence between Logan and his family, primarily his mother, Sue Nabors Noble, his wife, Nedda Harrigan Logan, and his stepsister, Lois Noble Smith. Logan's early years are reflected in his school and military papers. A group of files labeled “mental health” document his struggle with manic depression and his involvement with Merrill Moore, a noted psychiatrist. A small genealogical section contains photocopied records of the Lee,; Lockwood, and Logan families as well as a few original eighteenth and nineteenth century letters and documents.
The General Correspondence series in the collection contains letters from Logan's friends, colleagues, and the general public. Notable are Zinn Arthur,; Irving Berlin,; Bennett Cerf,; Oscar Hammerstein,; Leland Hayward,; William Inge,; Mary Martin,; James A. Michener,; Jo Mielziner,; Richard Rodgers,; Rosalind Russell,; James Stewart, and Emlyn Williams. Additional correspondence from individuals can be located in the Production File under the shows with which they were associated. For example, letters from Mary Martin appear with material on South Pacific and the production of Miss Moffat in 1974.
The Business Papers reflect Logan's multifaceted involvement in the theater world as well as his personal business matters. Correspondence with agents includes management of Logan's career in addition to employment inquiries from authors and actors. The financial papers include Logan's investments in theater productions and the stock market. Correspondence with Logan's entertainment lawyers in the legal section contains much information on the preparation of his shows, as do the interoffice memoranda and office diaries. The projects section contains idea files and material related to the many properties on which Logan held or negotiated an option but never actually mounted. Shows staged with his active participation are represented with various materials in the Production File.
The Production File consists of papers relating to the preparation and management of shows in which Logan was personally connected as director, producer, author, or actor. Also included are productions for which Logan was hired but from which he resigned before the show opened. In cases where Logan was involved in both the stage and screen version of a work, separate files have been maintained. Subjects relate to casting, financial management, legal matters, derivative productions such as touring companies and amateur performances, publicity, research, reviews, and tickets, including benefit shows. The working papers sections contain correspondence and notes on rehearsals, performance quality, plot development, script revisions, costumes, set design, location arrangements, equipment, and editing. The amount of material on each show varies greatly. Some productions, such as South Pacific, are well documented, while others, such as By Jupiter, have very little information. Related material can be found in the Business Papers under legal papers, interoffice memoranda, and office diaries. The Miscellany series contains scrapbooks for most of the major shows with which Logan was associated.
The Writings File, arranged alphabetically by author, includes scripts submitted to Logan for his consideration or advice. The scripts listed under Logan's name are those in which he was actively engaged in writing or revising. Logan's writings also include articles, books, poetry, short stories, song lyrics, and speeches. Related material, such as contracts, correspondence, outlines, notes, publicity, reviews, and royalty statements, accompany Logan's drafts.
The Miscellany series primarily contains newspaper and magazine clippings about Logan and his family. Pamphlets relating to Konstantin Stanislavsky are filed with autographs and printed material. Other material includes awards, certificates, memoranda, scrapbooks for many of Logan's best-known productions, and a scrapbook containing original artwork from Logan's military school days.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Family Papers, 1723-1988
General Correspondence, 1907-1989
Business Papers, 1930-1989
Production File, 1903-1989
Writings File, 1925-1988
Miscellany, 1920-1992
Oversize, 1923-1986
Container List
- Family Papers, 1723-1988 (Box 1-16)
  Biographical data, genealogies, correspondence among family members, diaries, medical and mental health papers, and military records.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual or family group and therein by type of material.
  - Ash, Adelaide Harrigan (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1917, 1942-1960, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, undated
  - Colquitt, Eleanor H., 1951-1987, undated
  - Genealogy
    - Account books, 1772-1785, (2 folders)
    - Bible records and family charts, 1961, undated
    - Early correspondence, 1822-1876
    - Lee family, 1961, undated
    - Lockwood family, 1729-1874
    - Logan family, 1909-1934
    - Miscellany, 1723-1978, undated
    - Wills, 1729-1825
  - Harrigan family (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1919, 1930-1988, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, undated
  - Johnson family, 1933-1956, 1985-1987, undated
  - Leatherbee, Charles, 1933
  - Leatherbee, Mary Lee Logan
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1927-1929, 1949-1967, undated
      - Outgoing, 1925-1972, undated
    - Death of, 1972, undated
    - Estate papers, 1947-1978
    - Miscellany, 1928-1933, 1960-1977
  - Lester, Ann Connolly
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1950-1966, 1984
      - Outgoing, 1943-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Divorce papers, 1955, undated
    - Miscellany, 1950-1955, undated
  - Lester family, 1962-1975, undated
  - Logan family, 1915-1932, 1950-1987, undated
  - Logan, Joshua Lockwood
    - Biographical data, 1929-1985, undated, (3 folders)
    - Correspondence
      - Apr. 1923-Oct. 1927
      - Jan. 1928-Apr. 1944, (6 folders) (Box 4)
      - May 1944-Dec. 1987, undated, (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Death of, 1988, (3 folders); (7 folders) (Box 6)
    - Diaries, 1949-1964, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Medical papers, 1940, 1948-1986, undated
    - Mental health
      - 9 Dec. 1940-31 July 1941, (6 folders)
      - 1 Aug. 1941-circa 30 Nov. 1953, (8 folders) (Box 8)
      - 1 Dec. 1953-9 Oct. 1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Military papers
      - General, 1942-1945
      - Orders, 1943-1945
      - Training, 1943-1945, (2 folders)
    - School papers, 1923-1931, undated
    - Speech therapy, 1987-1988
  - Logan, Nedda Harrigan (Box 10)
    - Biographical data, 1967, undated
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1917, 1938-1968, 1988, undated
      - Outgoing, 1948-1986, undated, (3 folders)
    - Diaries, 1964
    - Miscellany, 1938-1953, 1983
  - Logan, Susan Adelaide Harrigan
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1957-1984, undated
      - Outgoing, 1959-1986, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1966-1968, undated
  - Logan, Thomas Heggen (Box 11)
    - Baby diary, 1950
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1951-1972, undated
      - Outgoing, 1956-1984, undated
    - Miscellany, 1951-1986, undated
  - Miscellaneous family correspondence, 1901-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nabors family, 1905-1938, 1987
  - Nabors, William Campbell
    - 1940, 1951-1952, (2 folders)
    - 1953-1958, 1974-1978 (Box 12)
  - Noble, Carolie, Desirée, and Marshall, 1925, 1948-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Noble family, 1927-1969, undated
  - Noble, Sue Nabors
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1926-1967, undated
      - Outgoing
        - Feb. 1911-Oct. 1931, (4 folders)
        - Nov. 1931-Oct. 1955, (6 folders) (Box 13)
        - Jan. 1956-Apr. 1975, undated, (5 folders) (Box 14)
    - Death of, 1976
    - Estate papers
      - Apr. 1976-Feb. 1977, (2 folders)
      - Mar. 1977-Oct. 1978 (Box 15)
    - Miscellany, 1907, 1918, 1933, undated
  - Smith, Lois Noble
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1973-1976
      - Outgoing
        - 1933-1976, (5 folders)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Estate papers, 1974-1978
    - Miscellany, 1960
- General Correspondence, 1907-1989 (Box 16-40)
  Letters to and from friends and business associates of Joshua and Nedda Logan.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Abbott, George, 1962, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Adams, Lee, 1963, 1970-1974, undated
  - Addams, Charles, 1964
  - Adler, Buddy, 1940, 1956-1959, undated
  - Aegis Theatre Club, New York, N.Y., 1950-1955, undated
  - Agence Maritime Internationale, 1960
  - Albert and Mary Lasker Foundation, 1987
  - Albert Parvin & Co., 1968-1969, undated
  - Alexander, Ruth, 1952
  - Allen, Ralph, 1978, undated
  - American embassy, London, Eng., 1956, 1975-1977
  - American Express Co., 1948, 1963, 1976
  - American National Theatre and Academy, New York, N.Y., 1950-1954, 1960-1965, 1974, undated
  - American Red Cross, 1949-1964, 1985-1987
  - American Theatre Association, 1983
  - American Theatre Wing, 1948-1961, 1987, undated
  - American University, Washington, D.C., 1982-1985, undated
  - Anderson, Maxwell, 1948-1953
  - Anderson, Robert, 1958, 1967, undated
  - Arellano family, 1950, 1956-1960, undated
  - Army Theatre Arts Associaton, 1978
  - Arthur, Zinn, 1949-1987, undated (Box 17)
  - Asia Society, 1958
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1950-1952, 1958
  - Awe, Jim, 1953-1958
  - Axelrod, George and Joan, 1959-1967, 1973-1976, undated
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1943-1988, undated, (5 folders)
  - Ballard, Lucinda, 1949, 1955-1960, undated (Box 18)
  - Baralt, Luis A., 1947-1949
  - Barnett, Lincoln, 1950-1952, undated
  - Baum, Martin, 1954-1956
  - Beaumont, Hugh, 1948-1956, 1970, undated
  - Beckhard, Arthur J., 1933
  - Behrman, S. N., 1950-1973, undated
  - Belmore, Bertha, undated
  - Berlin, Irving, 1949-1955, 1962, 1968-1977, 1987, undated
  - Bernstein, Herman, 1952-1955, 1963
  - Bernstein, Leonard and Felicia, 1953, 1961, undated
  - Blair, Janet, 1952, undated
  - Bloomgarden, Kermit, 1956, 1972
  - Blore, Clara, 1958-1961
  - Bolger, Ray, 1987
  - Bousquet, Marie-Louise, 1958-1964, undated
  - Bower, Faubion, 1953-1963, undated
  - Boyer, Charles, 1952-1962, undated
  - Brisson, Frederick, 1954-1956, 1964-1967, 1973, undated
  - Brown, Helen Gurley, 1976
  - Brynner, Yul, 1953, 1985
  - Buchwald, Art, 1959-1960, 1968, 1977
  - The Buckley School, New York, N.Y., 1955-1965
  - Burton, Richard, 1953, 1961, undated
  - Buttons, Red, undated
  - “Ba-Berl” miscellaneous, 1940-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - “Berm-Bz” miscellaneous, 1931, 1940-1987, undated, (8 folders) (Box 19)
  - Cahn, Sammy, 1976
  - Campbell, Alan, 1949-1952, 1959, undated
  - Capote, Truman, 1965, undated
  - Carlisle, Kitty, 1949, 1959-1968, undated See also Container 24, Hart, Moss
  - Caron, Leslie, 1960, 1986, undated
  - Cerf, Bennett and Phyllis, 1951-1970, undated
  - Chan, Sou, 1950-1956
  - Chapman, John, 1948
  - Chayefsky, Paddy, 1955-1961, undated
  - Chevalier, Maurice, 1958-1962, 1969
  - Choate School, Wallingford, Conn., 1949-1950, 1958-1975, undated
  - Chodorov, Jerome, 1961-1963, 1976
  - Churchill, Winston S., 1964-1970, undated
  - Colbert, Claudette, 1954, 1975, 1980, undated
  - Cole, Kenneth L., 1957-1963, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Columbia Pictures Corp., 1953-1956, 1986, undated
  - Compana, Joyce, 1960
  - Connaught Hotel, London, Eng., 1953, 1960, 1970
  - Cook, Ida and Louise, 1968-1972, undated
  - Cooper, Jackie, 1950-1951
  - Cowles family, 1952-1959, 1966-1969, 1975, undated
  - Crane, Frances and Robert, 1932, 1943-1954, 1960, 1970, undated
  - Crawford, Joan, 1951-1961
  - Crawley, Lawrence, 1946, 1961
  - Cukor, George Dewey, 1958, 1964-1967
  - Culver Military Academy, Culver, Ind., 1927, 1941, 1948-1966, 1979-1987, (2 folders)
  - “Ca-Ce” miscellaneous, 1948-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - “Ch-Cz” miscellaneous, 1940-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 21)
  - Davis, Bette, 1951-1952, 1961, undated
  - Davis, Ossie, 1965-1969
  - Davis, Tobé, 1960-1962
  - “Da” miscellaneous, 1933, 1940-1941, 1947-1989, undated
  - “Dc-Dz” miscellaneous, 1940-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Ellis, Michael, 1960-1961, 1972
  - Engel, Lehman, 1950-1955, 1961-1966, undated
  - Epstein, Julius J., 1960-1964, 1987
  - Evans, Robert H., 1961, 1967
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1940, 1948-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - Fabray, Nanette, 1966
  - Fairbanks, Douglas, 1958, 1970, 1976, 1986
  - Feibleman, Peter S., 1962-1968, undated
  - Ferrer family, 1949-1960, 1974, 1984-1988, undated
  - Fields, Dorothy and Herbert, 1949-1954, 1972, undated
  - Fisher, Eddie, undated
  - Fitelson, H. William, 1952-1955, 1966, 1976-1980, undated
  - Fonda, Henry, 1948-1963, 1975-1978, undated
  - Fonda, Jane, 1952, 1961, 1979, undated (Box 23)
  - Fonda, Peter, 1948, 1968, undated
  - Fontanne, Lynn, undated See also Container 27, Lunt, Alfred
  - The Ford Foundation, 1952, 1958-1959
  - Fredericks, Ellsworth, 1957, 1963
  - Fuller, Frances, 1955, 1962, 1972
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1931, 1940-1941, 1948-1988, undated, (4 folders)
  - Gaffiot, Bluette, 1959-1960, undated
  - Geddes, Norman Bel, 1950-1955, undated
  - Gillmore, Margalo, 1953-1960, 1968-1969, 1978, undated
  - Goetz, Edie and William, 1956-1964, 1978, undated
  - Gordon, Max, 1952, 1960
  - Grace, Princess of Monaco, 1967, 1977, 1987, undated
  - Gregg, Jess, 1954
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1940, 1948-1987, undated, (4 folders) (Box 24)
  - Hall, Juanita, 1949-1953, 1961
  - Halliday, Richard, 1949-1952, 1961, undated See also Container 29, Martin, Mary
  - Hamilton, Nancy, 1966, undated
  - Hammerstein, Dorothy, 1948-1970, 1986, undated
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1947-1960, undated
  - Hammerstein, William, 1948-1965, 1976, 1985-1987
  - Hanighen, Bernard D., 1950-1952
  - Hapgood, Elizabeth R., 1949-1952, 1958-1972, undated
  - Harrison, Rex, 1959, 1975
  - Hart, Moss, 1952-1960, undated See also Container 19, Carlisle, Kitty
  - Hartley, Neil C., 1963-1964, 1970-1972, 1978, undated
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1951-1960
  - Hayes, Helen, 1949-1960, 1968-1969, undated
  - Hayward, Brooke, 1976, undated
  - Hayward, Leland, 1940, 1947-1968, undated (Box 25)
  - Heggen, Thomas, 1948-1972, 1980
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1950-1955, 1961, 1968, undated
  - Henderson, Florence, 1965, undated
  - Herlihy, James Leo, 1958-1962
  - Hopper, Hedda, 1955-1964, undated
  - Hornblow, Arthur, 1956-1958, 1967-1969
  - Houghton, Norris, 1950-1960, undated
  - Hudson, Rock, 1976
  - “Had-Hom” miscellaneous, 1923, 1930, 1940-1987, undated, (4 folders)
  - “Hop-Hz” miscellaneous, 1946-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - Inge, William, 1953-1969, undated
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1953-1976, 1986, undated
  - Jamison, Marshall, 1950-1955, 1976, 1982, 1987, undated
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1948-1987, undated, (3 folders)
  - Kadish, Ben, 1958-1963, 1970, undated
  - Kanin, Garson, 1949-1950, 1960-1965, 1975, undated
  - Kaye, Sylvia Fine, 1953, 1967, 1980-1981, 1987, undated
  - Kazan, Elia, 1949-1966, 1978-1980, undated
  - Kelley, Beverly, 1951-1955, undated
  - Kelly, Grace See Container 23, Grace, Princess of Monaco
  - Kendrigan, James H., 1949-1953 (Box 27)
  - Kennedy family, 1961-1963, undated
  - Kerr, Jean, 1964, undated
  - Khan, Amyn Aga, undated
  - Kidd, Michael, 1954
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1953-1956, 1975
  - Klopfer, Donald S., 1954, 1980
  - Kober, Arthur, 1952-1957, undated
  - Krasna, Norman, 1947-1958, 1969, 1976, undated
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1933, 1940-1941, 1948-1987, undated, (4 folders)
  - Lancaster, Burt, 1962
  - Langner, Lawrence, and Armina Marshall, 1940, 1953-1963, undated See also Container 28, Marshall, Armina
  - Laughlin, Tom, 1954-1960
  - Leachman, Cloris, 1976
  - Lemmon, Jack, undated
  - Lerner, Alan Jay, 1956-1967, 1974-1978, undated
  - Linden, Robert, 1948-1953, 1976-1978, undated
  - Lindsay, Howard, 1950-1955
  - Loewe, Frederick, 1960-1961, 1986, undated
  - Long Ridge School, Stamford, Conn., 1954-1955, undated
  - Loos, Anita, 1947-1968, undated
  - Lunt, Alfred, 1949, undated See also Container 23, Fontanne, Lynn
  - Lyons, Leonard, 1954-1958, undated
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1939-1987, undated, (6 folders) (Box 28)
  - MacLaine, Shirley, undated
  - MacLane, Charlotte, 1949-1951, 1964-1969, 1975, undated
  - Mahoney, Florence, 1957-1959, 1968-1969
  - March, Fredric, 1950, 1961
  - Marshall, Armina, 1945, 1954, 1963-1965, undated See also Container 27, Langner, Lawrence
  - Martin, Hugh, 1985-1988, undated
  - Martin, Mary, and Richard Halliday, 1949-1976, 1986, undated See also Container 24, Halliday, Richard (Box 29)
  - Martin, Peter, 1954
  - Marvin, Lee, 1969-1972, 1987, undated
  - Marx, Groucho, 1961
  - Matthau, Walter, 1963-1965, undated
  - Maxwell, Elsa, 1953-1955, 1961-1962, undated
  - McCormick, Frank, 1948-1950
  - McCormick, Myron, 1949-1953
  - McEvoy, J. P. and Peggy, 1950-1963
  - Merman, Ethel, undated
  - Merrick, David, 1953-1963
  - Merrill, Beth, 1953-1954, 1960-1964, undated
  - Messel, Oliver and Vagn, 1953-1966, undated
  - Michener, James A., 1955-1956, 1965, 1984-1987, undated
  - Middleton, Ray, 1950-1953, 1959-1965, 1976, undated
  - Mielziner, Jo, 1948-1968, undated
  - Miller, Arthur, 1955, 1962
  - Miller, Gilbert, 1940, 1950-1966, undated
  - Miscellaneous, 1949-1958, undated
  - Miyazawa, Arthur N., 1955-1965, 1975, 1984-1987, undated
  - Moody, Richard, 1972-1976, undated
  - Moonjean, Hank, 1959-1963, 1975-1978, 1984, undated
  - Moore, Burness E., 1949, 1964
  - Mundy, Pleasance, 1952-1956, 1963-1966, undated
  - Murray, Don, 1956, undated
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, N.Y., 1955, 1969-1970
  - Museum of the City of New York, New York, N.Y., 1955-1956, 1969-1986, undated
  - Music Corporation of America, 1953-1962, 1968 (Box 30)
  - “Ma-Mi” miscellaneous, 1931, 1940-1987, undated, (5 folders)
  - “Mo-Mz” miscellaneous, 1948-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 31)
  - New Dramatists Committee, New York, N.Y., 1949-1965, 1972-1974, 1984-1986, undated
  - Newman, Paul, 1958-1963, 1987
  - Nielsen, Jack and Jan, 1975-1978
  - Norton, Elliot, 1954, 1962, 1975-1976, 1982